Ahmad Zia WASI

Administrative Assistant | Powercoders Participant

Hauptstrasse 26, 6315 Oberägeri | 01.01.1990 Residence permit B | Single | (Afghanistan) ahmadzia.wasi@powercoders.org | +41 78 205 90 03

GitHub | Online portfolio | LinkedIn

Languages: English (B2), German (A2), Hindi/Urdu(A2),

Pashto/Dari (mother tongue)

IT skills: Intermediate: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL

Elementary: ERD Design, Accounting, Privacy by Design concept Beginner: Python, C#, Visual Basic, Computer Hardware, Agile

Methodology.

SUMMARY

As a holder of a bachelor in computer science and nine years of administrative experience, I am looking forward to a challenging position to make the best use of my experience and IT skills. I believe I am the ideal candidate for the positions that require both business and technical IT skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

06/2019 – 02/2020 Administrative Assistant, Janus Global Operations, Kabul (Afghanistan)

- Led the night shift personnel in the US Embassy.

Nine month night shift operations without incident.

11/2018 – 05/2019 Compliance Officer, Albashir Exchange, Kabul (Afghanistan)

- Monitored over 500 transactions daily basis.

- Maintained high compliance awareness in organization.

11/2015 – 05/2018 Operations Coordinator Assistant (80%), Janus Global Operations, Kabul

(Afghanistan)

- Received promotion in the first 4 months.

Successfully implemented the new SOP.

09/2015 – 05/2017 Concurrent Audit (50%), Maiwand Bank, Kabul (Afghanistan)

- Successfully audited the biggest branch.

Best audit award receiver.

01/2012 – 09/2015 SWIFT and CSO Supervisor Maiwand Bank, Kabul (Afghanistan)

- Organized and merged the filing system consisting over 2000 Accounts data.

- Appreciation award for 2012.

04/2011 – 12/2011 CSO Officer Maiwand Bank, Kabul (Afghanistan)

- Established regulatory procedures for Account Opening.

EDUCATION

09/2021 – 12/2021 Powercoders – Coding Academy for Refugees, Zurich (Switzerland)

- Foundations in HTML, CSS, JavaScript; specialization tracks upcoming

- Weekly business & social skills training (team work, communication, etc.)

03/2011 – 12/2014 Bachelor of Computer Science, Kardan University, Kabul (Afghanistan)

- Database specializations, SQL, C#Overall GPA 3.68 on scale of 4.00.

06/2009 – 06/2010 Diploma in Business Administrations, Capital College, Peshawar (Pakistan)

- MS Office, Accounting, Auditing & Customer Service.

06//2007 – 06/2010 12th grade, Khushal Khan High School, Peshawar (Pakistan)

CONTINUOUS EDUCATION

06/2010 – 07/2010 Potential teachers training course, Ghairat Educational Institute, Peshawar

(Pakistan).

06/2019 TOEFL IBT score of 86, Online, Educational Testing Service (ETS USA).

01/2021 – 09/2021 German Language A2, ProArbeit Zug.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

08-2018 – 04/2019 Database Developer, Extra Reliable Software House, Kabul (Afghanistan)

- Successfully leaded Money Exchange and Stationery Management system

projects.

HOBBIES

Programming, HTML, CSS & SQL.

Browsing for new cyber security stuff in my free time. Watching Hollywood and Bollywood Action movies.

REFERENCES

Hussam Allaham Industry Lead, Powercoders Deutschschweiz,

hussam.allaham@powercoders.org, +41 77 906 16 27

Vera Geissbühler Asylum Social Services, Kanton Zug.

vera.geissbuehler@zg.ch, + 41 41 723 66 70